Erin Hinson

Experienced Front End Engineer with extensive experience building software in both onsite and remote team environments. Strong SaaS experience with an eye for design and exceptional mindfulness for scalability, code quality and user experience. Excellent reputation as a team leader, collaborator, and web developer, with passion for taking on complex problems and helping drive solutions that positively impact both the products and people involved.

EMPLOYMENT

2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FRONT END APPLICATIONS- Musicbed

Reporting to the Front End Team Lead, migrate filmsupply.com from an Angular 1 app to React.

- + Maintain a component library with Storybook
- + Use Unstated and Hooks for state management

2017 - 2020

FRONT END ENGINEER-Treetop Commons, LLC

Lead Front End Engineer (2019-2020)

Reporting to the VP Engineering & Product, promoted to lead local and remote team of front end engineers during a period of extensive internal change, focusing on both building and maintaining NobleHour and Collaboratory SaaS and mobile products, as well as mentoring and coaching staff.

Front End Engineer (2017-2019)

Reporting to the Front End Lead, collaborated with front end development team along with API, QA and DevOps to build and maintain NobleHour and Collaboratory SaaS and mobile products. Maintained component library, migrated legacy codebase, and worked toward WCAG 2.1 AA accessibility compliance. Led yearlong project to rewrite Add/Edit Hours feature, migrating from ComponentJS to React. Built & introduced multiple logic & flow improvements and enhanced complex feature set.

- + Use React, Redux, AWS, Golang
- + Use Jest and Enzyme for test coverage
- + Maintain a component library with Storybook
- + Migrate a large legacy codebase (Golang, JQuery, ComponentJS) to React
- + Work toward WCAG 2.1 AA accessibility compliance

2015 - 2017

FRONT END DEVELOPER-Xceleration Inc

Reporting to the Front End Architect, developed and maintained responsive apps, banners, landing pages and emails for client programs. Conducted cross-browser testing and troubleshooting, identified potential issues and implemented fixes as necessary.

- Use ReactJS, Redux, Flow, Styled Components, Middleman, Gulp, Webpack and Bootstrap with Rails and .NET backends
- + Continuous delivery with Jenkins
- + Conduct cross-browser testing and troubleshooting with Browserstack.

2015

UX DEVELOPER - Technekes, LLC

- + Developed app mockups and prototypes, utilizing HTML/HAML, CSS/SASS, Javascript/JQuery, and Middleman, with a Rails backend.
- + Coded and tested HTML email campaigns.

2015

INSTRUCTOR: POP-UP CODE - Tech Talent South

+ Taught a 2-week web development program on Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap, APIs, RESTful apps, and database modeling associations.

EDUCATION

2014

2012 - 2014

TECH TALENT SOUTH- Ruby on Rails Bootcamp

TECHNICAL COMMUNICATIONS- Metropolitan State University

Coursework in Computer Science, Adobe Creative Suite, Technical Writing, and User Experience

2011

WEB AUTHORING CERTIFICATE- Front Range Community College Coursework in Javascript, CSS, HTML, Adobe Creative Suite, and PHP